I 'm certain that he 's a substance abuser .
Or is it a woman ?
Living in a small apartment , with her paranoia .
Her paranoia is of little interest to me .
But I can say this . By looking at her through the Iens ...
I believe that I 've salvaged her soul .
A tragedy occurred at a subway station .
Shot by freelance cameraman , Takuyoshi Masuoka
who happened to be at the scene of a bizarre suicide earlier today .
Don 't do it . calm down .
Keep out of here !
Let go of the knife .
calm down !
Arei Kuroki was without a steady income , just like me .
He was paying no attention to anybody at the site .
He was too terrified to notice them .
Did he stab himself in the eye to avoid seeing
what terrified him ?
I want to see what he saw then .
Among the images I 'd captured
there were strange images that looked like ghosts or UFOs .
Things both strange and mysterious .
But they mean nothing to me .
probably because these things have already been defined as strange .
Seeing these images makes the viewer feel anxious ...
unlike the look of absolute fear on that man 's face as he killed himself .
Even if this is really a person actually dying ...
The terror on her face doesn 't seem quite real .
If the ultimate terror is to have your own mind and body
destroyed by others ...
I 'd go so far as to imitate a psychopath
to record the terror of the victim on my retina and video tape .
I did not feel that sense of terror at all .
What is she looking at ?
Takuyoshi Masuoka who happened to be at the site of
a bizarre suicide earlier today .
He captured the incident in close proximity ...
What was he watching that was so terrifying ?
The answer was underground ...
I quit taking the prozac to control my serotonin level .
I have to stay focused .
Otherwise I won 't see what I 'm dying to see .
They weren 't terrified to see whatever they saw .
They saw something because they were terrified .
I had it all wrong .
I was with a documentary TV crew on that day .
We were on our way back from a shoot .
Now I 'm back at the scene ...
And I realize that the image on the TV is more realistic .
What did Kuroki see ?
Do I have the courage to open the door to the passageway of terror ?
Can I face terror from which the only escape is to kill myself ?
Fear of the unknown compels me to open the door .
These stairs were built not so long ago .
Beneath Tokyo lay hidden tunnels and passageways .
It 's a weII-known urban myth .
But obviously it 's not just a myth .
The underground development was a reminder of the second world war .
This must be one such war time memorabilia .
Stay away !
Sorry to bother you ...
homeless people usually stay in populated areas .
But not this one . He rejects society completely .
Why is he so alarmed ? What 's he scared of ?
It 's so safe down here ...
Safe ?
It 's not safe at all .
Why not ... ?
Because of the " Deros " .
" DEROs " ?
If they find you ...
they 'II suck your blood dry .
He is definitely haunted by terror .
The underground development of Tokyo was not ...
just from the second world war .
It must have been done throughout history .
Connecting new tunnels with old ones .
Who 's beyond the wall ?
Who hides behind it ?
I 've crossed the boundary to the netherworld alive .
It must mean that I 'm sufficiently terrified .
I 've been invited here .
Invited by who ? And why ?
I 'm too exhausted to think straight .
I 'm not sure if I can make logical conclusions .
I haven 't seen you around .
Are you new here ?
This must be the netherworld .
Many think that beneath the earth is the netherworld .
It 's because they don 't know what 's underneath .
It 's widely conceived as the world beyond .
Mr. Kuroki , you 're a talkative ghost , aren 't you ?
Do you think I 'm really a ghost ?
My name is actually Kuroki .
Have we met ?
No .
You haven 't seen me before but I 've seen you .
I saw you through the viewfinder .
You are different from those who come here to escape .
I just saw one of them .
I saw him back there .
But I don 't think I 'm all that different from these people .
I didn 't know that Tokyo had such a developed subterranean complex .
It 's not just Tokyo .
populated places all over the world all have access
to the underground world .
Are you referring to the hollow Earth Theory ?
As you know , there are two versions of the theory .
One version is that the earth is hollow like an eggshell .
Another view is that there is a complex subterranean system .
I 'm short of evidence to support the former version .
The latter seems true as we stand in that very complex .
Entrances to the subterranean world do exist in South America .
It 's a well known fact that underneath brussels lays a subterranean city .
below the PataIa shrine in Tibet
there 's a utopia called ShambaIIa . A very well accepted idea .
And Agartha is its capital ...
It 's history as foreseen by Madame BIavatsky .
By the way , the under dweller I stumbled upon earlier ...
He was very afraid of the Deros .
It 's short for the detrimental robots .
They are indeed dangerous .
They can hardly see but like dogs they hear well .
You 'd better be careful .
Right ... I 'm beginning to remember ...
Is it the creature described by Richard Shaver
in the fantasy book he wrote in the 20s ?
It was a book of fiction .
until the book turned out to be a prophesy .
Then fiction was no Ionger fiction .
I see .
You 're saying that the Shaver Mystery was fictional when it was written .
Now it 's recognized as the truth as well as the hollow earth theory .
You 're a quick learner .
Wait a minute .
I understand nothing yet .
I want to know what was so terrifying when you died .
The horror I saw on your face ...
I came here wanting to find that out .
So you 're saying that I 'm dead .
I lost my Iife before I reached Agartha .
If I really died in front of you
you shouldn 't be with me like this .
Wait ...
It doesn 't matter if I have lost my mind .
But I want to stay sane enough to recognize the terror .
The Moutntains Of Madness .
There must be ancient ruins down in the ravines .
This is not the creation of man but of the under dwellers .
I know I 'm not the only living being here .
I can feel it .
Sorry to have kept you waiting . I 'm Mori .
Isn 't it hot in here ?
So Mr. Masuoka , are you a trained news cameraman ?
Not just that but my last company was affiliated with the news .
We do industrial videos , too .
Sometimes even TV dramas . Anything goes .
We can register you as camera crew .
When we have a production , we 'II put you down for it .
That 's fine .
deal , then .
Here 's the one .
The main feature is the " movie mode " . A video telecast function .
Do you have a pet , by any chance ?
You can check how your cat 's doing from wherever you are .
Great image quality . We only have one left .
would you Iike to buy it ? Thank you very much .
I decided to tentatively call her " F " .
Not that I actually call her by that name .
My little Kaspar Hauser .
I don 't know how old she is but obviously
this is the first time for her to meet a human .
I wipe her once a day and that 's all I can do for her .
F doesn 't eat nor drink anything .
She 's only awake for 3 hours or so .
This is Atsuko Ono in Shinjuku .
I 'II show you the latest fashion trends so check them out .
Let 's see what I can find ...
Any young couples ? Let 's have a look .
Over there !
Excuse me . Want to be on TV ?
Stop the camera ! They don 't look like they 're in love .
Lose this thing !
Sorry .
We 're moving .
The next location ...
It 's right over there .
A new boutique in the mail .
Not again !
Just a little interview .
MA-SU-O-KA TA-KU-YO-SHI
MA-SU-O-KA ...
Maybe her vocal cords are impaired from being inactive .
She came from a world where vocaIizing was unnecessary .
How old is your daughter ?
No , she 's not my daughter ...
Is this a gift then ? How tall is she ?
150 ? Maybe 160 cm ...
In that case ...
How about this ? This is so pretty . It 's popular now .
This one will look great on her .
I think I want something plain ...
plain ... ?
Who 's F talking to ?
What 's wrong ? What 's happened ?
Hey ?
What 's wrong ?
You should have drunk what I gave you !
12 seconds ...
What happened in those 12 seconds ?
hello .
Who is this ?
Who I am is irrelevant to the problem that you have .
You have the wrong number . I 'm not ...
I have the right number , Mr. Masuoka .
You 're in serious trouble . Do you realize that ?
What are you talking about ?
There 's someone there who shouldn 't be .
She can 't survive there . Do you understand me ?
You think that you 're saving her life .
But you 're actually killing her .
What can I do ?
She eats nothing , drinks nothing !
tell me what I 'm supposed to do !
" From public pay phone "
should I just observe F as she weakens ?
What do I expect from her ?
Even if she could be taught to behave like a human ...
what would she gain from that ?
What are you recording ?
Nothing .
You were recording me . I saw you .
It was turned off .
I don 't like it . Give me the tape .
What 's the matter ? Did you do something wrong ?
Okay , wise-ass . Give it up !
Hand it over .
Give it to me !
hello . I 'm back .
Were you sleeping all day again ?
It 's nothing . I slipped .
I liked it .
I wanted to keep feeding her .
until she 's totally satisfied .
Of course what it means is my own death .
I don 't care if I died but ...
what would happen to her if I died ?
She didn 't complain much about animal blood but ...
Nothing made her content like human blood .
I gave up treating her like a human .
I treat her like an animal , Iike a pet .
That 's all she should be for me .
That 's all I should care for her .
recently she has begun to behave like a human .
That 's probably ...
just her imitating me .
What is F anyway ?
Why does she only feed on blood ?
My speculation is that from the day of her birth
she was raised on blood instead of breast milk .
No human would have done it .
It must be someone from underground .
Perhaps I can assume that the " Deros " brought her up .
Hey ...
Did you hurt yourself ?
Who are you ?
What 's wrong with you ? Listen to me .
Are you joking ? Fuyumi 's missing .
I told the police already .
But I ...
Fuyumi ?
Is she with you now ?
I don 't know any Fuyumi . I 'm innocent .
Don 't know her ? She 's your daughter .
I don 't have a daughter .
Madness is contagious .
recently I attract madness . I wonder why ...
If she left my apartment on her own will ...
She 's not so far away . She can hardly walk .
But if somebody took her away ...
I 'm not giving up F.
I found her .
I want her back .
please tell me ...
Has she gone back to the subterranean ruins ?
So you failed , didn 't you ?
I had a little hope that you might be the one who could tame her .
What did she eat when she was away ?
I don 't have any idea .
But one thing is clear .
She needs nutritious food desperately .
Don 't walk away !
You have to listen to me .
You owe me an explanation .
Are you going to ignore me forever ?
I 'm going to make you talk today .
Stop pretending that you know nothing !
Hey !
Stop treating me like shit !
Stop !
I know you can hear me .
I know Fuyumi 's with you .
I want to see her .
I know you 're hiding her . So stop pretending !
Say something .
I have a right to see my girl ...
Do you always take that video camera with you ?
You 're a pervert , right ?
You have to make me look pretty .
Never tell the school about this .
I 'm dead meat if they found out .
Are you going to sell this ? Give me 50,000 , then .
50,000 yen is enough ?
I should have made it 100,000 .
What are you drinking ? Are you hungry ?
It 's Iow-caI diet food .
I have a hungry girl back at home , too .
So ? Are we going to have the interview here ?
I lost my virginity ...
When was that ?
Was it yesterday ? Or was it the day before that ?
Over there ?
Are you serious ? I don 't think so .
There are better places than this .
What are you ?
Throat fetish ?
Anybody in fear is beautiful .
But if it 's fear of death , it 's mediocre .
I don 't recognize myself any more .
" call from public pay phone "
hello ?
F is content now .
Because I made her content .
You should have nothing to complain about now .
No complaints . You 're right .
roll camera , Masuoka .
Are you ready , Tanaka ?
Action in 5 seconds , 4 , 3 , 2 ...
Reporting from the murder site .
At a public toilet not long ago ,
a high school girl was found dead .
No sign of theft , her personal belongings were found intact .
The police has been examining the site for further evidence .
The victim has not been identified yet .
We 'II give you updates as information comes through .
Good , cut !
Okay .
Masuoka , we 're done here . Let 's go .
Masuoka ... ?
I think humans are a degenerated species .
I believe that our ancestors were more perceptive than us .
They could see creatures from a different dimension ...
sneaking into our dimension ...
The creatures ... The strangers ...
Come on , Iet 's go .
That 's enough .
You 've had enough .
I took a train without deciding on a destination .
I don 't remember how long I 've been here .
I might as well find ajob in the village .
And work until the day I die .
Maybe that 's how my Iife should be .
Do you want to come home ?
Home ... ?
We have come from the depths of the ocean .
Have you forgotten that ?
No , I haven 't .
crawling under tremendous water pressure ,
our people used to be so much wiser then .
What did you see ?
When you poked your eye out in the subway tunnel .
You looked as if you 'd seen something most terrifying .
Yes ... That 's right .
I don 't know why ...
But I long for your terror .
I long to experience the terror that you 'd felt .
That 's because it 's something unknown .
The feeling we know as terror ...
is actually ancient wisdom that 's sealed in our subconscious mind .
So I wasn 't really mad .
It was just pretence .
I longed to be mad . I just hoped to be so mad
that I couId someday witness the terror .
As a result , I killed my wife .
And treated my daughter like an animal .
I even killed somebody unrelated .
AII of that was not enough to drive me truly insane .
That 's how degenerated I am .
A " Dero " ?
The creature still exists in my apartment .
Looks like she 's hibernating ...
You ...
came back to me ...
From now on I 'II never speak .
Because I need no human words now .